<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lime on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</title>
    <link>/tags/lime/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lime on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/lime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HH Data Science Meetup slides: Explaining complex machine learning models with LIME</title>
      <link>/2018/04/hh_datascience_meetup_2018_slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/hh_datascience_meetup_2018_slides/</guid>
      <description>On April 12th, 2018 I gave a talk about Explaining complex machine learning models with LIME at the Hamburg Data Science Meetup - so if you’re intersted: the slides can be found here: https://www.slideshare.net/ShirinGlander/hh-data-science-meetup-explaining-complex-machine-learning-models-with-lime-94218890
 Traditional machine learning workflows focus heavily on model training and optimization; the best model is usually chosen via performance measures like accuracy or error and we tend to assume that a model is good enough for deployment if it passes certain thresholds of these performance criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing my talk about explainability of machine learning models at Minds Mastering Machines conference</title>
      <link>/2018/02/m3_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/m3_2018/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday, April 25th 2018 I am going to talk about explainability of machine learning models at the Minds Mastering Machines conference in Cologne. The conference will be in German, though.
  ERKLÄRBARKEIT VON MACHINE LEARNING: WIE KÖNNEN WIR VERTRAUEN IN KOMPLEXE MODELLE SCHAFFEN?
  Mit Machine-Learning getroffene Entscheidungen sind inhärent schwierig – wenn nicht gar unmöglich – nachzuvollziehen. Die Komplexität einiger der besten Modelle, wie Neuronale Netzwerke, ist genau das, was sie so erfolgreich macht.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking beyond accuracy to improve trust in machine learning</title>
      <link>/2018/01/looking_beyond_accuracy_to_improve_trust_in_ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/looking_beyond_accuracy_to_improve_trust_in_ml/</guid>
      <description>I have written another blogpost about Looking beyond accuracy to improve trust in machine learning at my company codecentric&amp;rsquo;s blog:
 Traditional machine learning workflows focus heavily on model training and optimization; the best model is usually chosen via performance measures like accuracy or error and we tend to assume that a model is good enough for deployment if it passes certain thresholds of these performance criteria. Why a model makes the predictions it makes, however, is generally neglected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>