<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetup on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</title>
    <link>/tags/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetup on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Look, something shiny: How to use R Shiny to make Münster traffic data accessible. Join MünsteR for our next meetup!</title>
      <link>/2018/04/meetup_june18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/meetup_june18/</guid>
      <description>In our next MünsteR R-user group meetup on Monday, June 11th, 2018 Thomas Kluth and Thorben Jensen will give a talk titled Look, something shiny: How to use R Shiny to make Münster traffic data accessible. You can RSVP here: http://meetu.ps/e/F7zDN/w54bW/f
 About a year ago, we stumbled upon rich datasets on traffic dynamics of Münster: count data of bikes, cars, and bus passengers of high resolution. Since that day we have been crunching, modeling, and visualizing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HH Data Science Meetup slides: Explaining complex machine learning models with LIME</title>
      <link>/2018/04/hh_datascience_meetup_2018_slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/hh_datascience_meetup_2018_slides/</guid>
      <description>On April 12th, 2018 I gave a talk about Explaining complex machine learning models with LIME at the Hamburg Data Science Meetup - so if you’re intersted: the slides can be found here: https://www.slideshare.net/ShirinGlander/hh-data-science-meetup-explaining-complex-machine-learning-models-with-lime-94218890
 Traditional machine learning workflows focus heavily on model training and optimization; the best model is usually chosen via performance measures like accuracy or error and we tend to assume that a model is good enough for deployment if it passes certain thresholds of these performance criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup slides: Introducing Deep Learning with Keras</title>
      <link>/2018/04/ruhrpy_meetup_2018_slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/ruhrpy_meetup_2018_slides/</guid>
      <description>On April 4th, 2018 I gave a talk about Deep Learning with Keras at the Ruhr.Py Meetup in Essen, Germany. The talk was not specific to Python, though - so if you’re intersted: the slides can be found here: https://www.slideshare.net/ShirinGlander/ruhrpy-introducing-deep-learning-with-keras-and-python
  Ruhr.PY - Introducing Deep Learning with Keras and Python  von Shirin Glander  There is also a video recording of my talk, which you can see here: https://youtu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join MünsteR for our next meetup on deep learning with Keras and R</title>
      <link>/2018/03/meetup_april18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/meetup_april18/</guid>
      <description>In our next MünsteR R-user group meetup on Tuesday, April 17th, 2018 Kai Lichtenberg will talk about deep learning with Keras. You can RSVP here: http://meetu.ps/e/DDY1B/w54bW/f
 Although neural networks have been around for quite a while now, deep learning really just took of a few years ago. It pretty much all started when Alex Krizhevsky and Geoffrey Hinton utterly crushed classic image recognition in the 2012 ImageNet Large Scale Visual Recognition Challenge by implementing a deep neural network with CUDA on graphics cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My upcoming meetup talks about Deep Learning with Keras and explaining complex Machine Learning Models with LIME</title>
      <link>/2018/03/meetup_talk_ruhrpy_april_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/meetup_talk_ruhrpy_april_18/</guid>
      <description>I’ll be talking about Deep Learning with Keras in R and Python at the following upcoming meetup:
 Ruhr.Py 2018 on Wednesday, April 4th   Introducing Deep Learning with Keras and Python Keras is a high-level API written in Python for building and prototyping neural networks. It can be used on top of TensorFlow, Theano or CNTK. In this talk we build, train and visualize a Model using Python and Keras - all interactive with Jupyter Notebooks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join MünsteR for our next meetup on obtaining functional implications of gene expression data with R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/meetup_march18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/meetup_march18/</guid>
      <description>In our next MünsteR R-user group meetup on March 5th, 2018 Frank Rühle will talk about bioinformatics and how to analyse genome data.
You can RSVP here: http://meetu.ps/e/DDY1B/w54bW/f
 Next-Generation sequencing and array-based technologies provided a plethora of gene expression data in the public genomics databases. But how to get meaningful information and functional implications out of this vast amount of data? Various R-packages have been published by the Bioconductor user community for distinct kinds of analysis strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MICE (Multiple Imputation by Chained Equations) in R - sketchnotes from MünsteR Meetup</title>
      <link>/2017/11/mice_sketchnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/mice_sketchnotes/</guid>
      <description>Last night, the MünsteR R user-group had another great meetup:
Karin Groothuis-Oudshoorn, Assistant Professor at the University of Twente, presented her R package mice about Multivariate Imputation by Chained Equations.
It was a very interesting talk and here are my sketchnotes that I took during it:
MICE talk sketchnotes
Here is the link to the paper referenced in my notes: https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v045i03
“The mice package implements a method to deal with missing data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>